Christian Sheen

csheen1725@gmail.com (786)832-1691 Miami, United States linkedin.com/in/csheen github.com/blksmth1725

Software Engineer: Front End Developer

Software engineer who creatively solves problems to deliver seamless user experiences. I strive to understand people, technology, and how they interact to build useful applications/features. The goal is to help others bring their ideas to life through technology, helping them reach customers and grow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer | Pedra CRM LLC | Miami, FL 06/2021 - Present Building CRM system for existing API

- Currently working on an iOS app with SwiftUI and Apollo as my Graphql client which provides the same functionality as the web application. (iOS)
- Designing of 10+ Views performing queries with persisted user authorization via session tokens. (iOS)
- Built payment feature on web application to process transactions and store users' payment information in a secure manner. (Web Next.js)
- Using Graphql to query and mutate data with over 20 query/mutation endpoints resulting in 3 features moving into production. (Web Next.js)
- Learning about business logic for CRMs to give said features an intuitive feel, allowing users to create, modify or delete at many instances within their pipeline. (Web Next.js)

- Collaborated with the marketing team on 1-2 monthly campaigns to drive traffic towards our online platforms, resulting in 15% increase in online orders during COVID
- During Covid-19 peak: tasked with redesigning one of the locations. Created floor plans, renderings and designed new furniture. This resulted in 20% more square footage, which allowed us to provide guests with a safe dining experience.
- Created a process to track inventory and maintenance requirements across 6
 restaurants allowing the business to efficiently repair or replace machines
 resulting in no down time.

Architectural Assistant | Archimia | Miami, FL

07/2017 - 07/2018

Created and modified architectural drawings

- Authored 10 renders based on a residential project the firm was overseeing, resulting in the selection of materials/finishes which fit within the budget and satisfied clients aesthetic demands.
- Designing for over 800 hours in Revit. Contributed to 6 projects of which 4 I saw to completion.
- Sourced information from FBC & IBC to satisfy ADA, easement & egress, setback, FAR standards. Through proper implementation the business made fewer trips to the city for approval which improved delivery times.

EDUCATION + CERTIFICATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Bottega University, Utah (Remote)

01/2019 - 01/2020

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB

Certificate of completion

02/2021 - 03/2021

UDEMY, Node with React: Full stack Web Development

Certificate of completion

04/2021 - 05/2021

MERN stack front-back Web Development course

Architecture Associates in Art Miami Dade College, Miami, FL

08/2012 - 08/2014

Completed 70 credits hours toward a degree in Architectural Arts. Courses:

- Adv. Design Theory
- Arch Structures
- Environmental Sys in Arch

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Italian

Limited Working Proficiency